

NICOLAS A. VENZMER

FrontEnd Engineer

Frontend Engineer graduated in Information Technology Management. Specialized in React, Next.js and JavaScript. I have collaborated with backend engineers to integrate and consume APIs and with data scientists to identify and process relevant data. I implemented AI using Gen AI. Interested in new challenges to apply artificial intelligence and revolutionize the technology sector.

Contact

+54-11-5488-9200



nicovenz@gmail.com



www.nicolasvenzmer.com



Buenos Aires, Argentina

Education

 Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology Management

UADE

2021-2023

Languages

Spanish

Native

English

Advanced

German

Intermediate

Techincal Skills

Languages/Tools/Frameworks

ReactJS, JavaScript, NextJS, Redux, Styled Components, CSS, HTML, MongoDB, NodeJS, Jira, Bitbucket, Google Cloud

Professional Experience

Associate Software Engineer

R/GA

Mar 2022 - Present

- Dotcom Project Development:
 - Project: Refactored the company's web page to a newer version
 - Collaborated with graphic designers using Figma to develop a new version of the R/GA website.
 Implemented Next.js, and used JavaScript and Sass to optimize interactivity and design. I integrated
 Contentful as a CMS for more efficient content and media management.
- · Chat Bot:
 - Developed and maintained a chat bot using NextJS, JavaScript, CSS, and Custom Components, resulting in improved user engagement and satisfaction.
- Internal Slack Bot Integrated with GPT Assistant:
 - Engineered and integrated an internal Slack bot leveraging MongoDB, Node.js, Slack and GPT API, facilitating access to project information.
- Internal Data Platform:
 - I contributed to frontend development using JavaScript, ReactJS, Material-UI and Redux for state management. I implemented integrations with Apple, Amazon and Google for data mining and data-driven decisions.

Data Architect Intern

Globant

Sep 2021 - Mar 2022

I completed a Data Architect Trainee program, where I engaged in comprehensive training covering the following topics:

- Linux
- Python Programming
- Data Modeling & Cloud Technologies
- Hadoop Ecosystem
- Apache Spark

Certifications

Udemy - The Complete 2024 Web Development Bootcamp

Status - In Progress

Soon

Udemy - JavaScript University

Status - Completed

Jul 2021